Engineering]

Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Lingamaiah Manga 🚹 premium



Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, JavaSE, J2EE, Spring Boot, Microservices, Flask, Django, Algorithms, Data Structures, Java



Current Designation: Software Engineer

Current Company: CBRE South Asia Pvt Ltd.

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru /

Bangalore, Hyderabad, Secunderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, JavaSE, J2EE, Spring

Boot, Microservices, Flask, Django, Algorithms, Data Structures, Java

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

A programming geek and experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the software industry. Experienced in implementing micro services using Java, Python, Julia. Expert in data processing. Experienced in implementing web application end to end. Worked as R&D Engineer, Data Engineer, Full Stack Development, Software Development, Big data Development, Applications Development.Here is the my skill set matrix, Java Technologies, Data Processing Technologies, Programming Languages, Web Technologies, Scripting Languages, Data Bases RDBMS, Data Bases No SQL, Big data Technologies, Data Visualization Technologies. Web server (Tomcat, Nginx), Application server (Gunicorn), Load balancer.

Work Experience

CBRE South Asia Pvt Ltd. as Software Engineer

Oct 2019 to Till Date

Implemented a Java Microservices with Spring Boot for understanding the employees skill set matrix.

Implemented a Microservice APIs for Plans application using Julia language and

dockerized it.Implemented a utility for logs sync and rotation.

Implemented a chatbot Microservice API and deployed it on cloud microsoft Azure

App service.

Implemented a data migration utility, It copies the data from MsSQL/PostgreSQL source db, table to PostgreSQL/MsSQL target db, table.

Oracle India Pvt Ltd. as Applications Engineer

Jul 2018 to Oct 2019

Oracle HCM Cloud(Oracle Integrated Cloud Applications),implemented a algorithm to understand the all producs process execution time when scheduled. Optimized the tasks to finish it quickly.

Oracle HCM Simple Report Generator, It's a web application simple report generator on top of HCM result generator.

Oracle HCM Data Utilities, Implemented a data scanning engine for all the products master/child and other columns info. Storing the data in memory for quick access on large data sets. Used PySpark Created temp tables in memory, Implemented data generation engine from rest APIs using java. Mapped the search result to UI. Oracle HCM Click History, It's a production logs analysis and graph generation to track the user flow activity.

ADP India Pvt Ltd. as Member Technical

Oct 2016 to Jul 2018

Implemented a hybrid automation framework using Selenium/Java and introduced to QA in ADP.

Implemented a data processing pipeline for IRVP using big data technologies. Worked on RSVP/IRVP web application to enhance the functionalities.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from International Institute of Information Technology (IIIT), Idupulapaya in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experien	nce
JavaSE & J2EE		
spring boot		
MicroServices		
RESTful Services		
Flask & Django		
ALGORITHMS		
Data Structures		
Java8		
python3		
SQL & NoSQL		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time